How we doing?
Good.
Um
So, I mean overall I'd say kind of
continuation of some of the things we've
talked about in the off season, you
know, just building a tough, smart,
physical team.
Uh players that have the right mindset
and right mentality. Um so, um as far as
just
trades, positioning,
I'd say the the first pick with with
Caden, it's kind of moving a couple
slots, repositioning, kind of like we
did with Caylin or Caylin yeah, Caylin.
Uh you know, we felt McDonald was
probably the best run defender in the
draft. Um had a really productive
season, you know, a defensive tackle
that was involved in 60 tackles or 60
plus tackles, whatever it is.
Um it's pretty impressive. Um and we
just like the first unanimous defensive
tackle, unanimous All-American defensive
tackle in the history of Ohio State's
program. I mean, like
they've had a few decent players there.
So, um it's good kid, young kid. I mean,
played the season he's 20 years old. I
mean, he just turned 21. So,
um you know, I Map Patricia did a really
good job with him this year, got the
most out of him. Um guy was a good
player, you know, spent a lot of time
with him. So, feel our program will be a
good good fit. He'll be a good fit for
our program. Our program going to be a
good fit for him, but you know, what he
does well, he does it well. So, um you
know, that was him.
And then uh
you know, what 59, so we had multiple
discussions. We were kind of potentially
trading the pick, moving it. Had a few
deals in place, and those fell apart.
So, we had a couple guys that we were
talking about picking. Um and then, you
know, Marlon was one of them. I would
say for us Marlon like was kind of a
no-brainer. Um this is a player we
really liked. Um
his story, I mean, you guys will get to
if you haven't talked to him, like his
story is really impressive. Like the
fact that he's even here having this
discussion really speaks to who he is,
his maturity, his intelligence, his
toughness. I mean, he could have sat out
the bowl game, basically told his coach
and you know, everybody else's agents,
representatives, like I'm playing. I
mean, it's kind of like what Kamari did
the year that he came out, um you know,
with Georgia. So,
good size, runs well. I mean, 6'5" 250,
runs 4.6. Um you know, I'd say his best
football's probably in front of him.
But, type of player that has the right
mentality, has the right mindset, good
work ethic, really smart.
I'm sure we'll be playing in Germany
here, you know, one of these
international games. Get your passport
ready at some point. Um but, good
football player um who we uh visited
with at the combine.
Um really after the combine, like we
were kind of done with him as far as the
person. I mean, cuz there really wasn't
much more there that we needed to talk
about. So,
um you know, he was a player that we
liked. Um we liked him from the
beginning of the process um till
drafting him, which is, you know, why we
picked him.
Um and then with
So, we kind of repositioned uh the picks
there a little bit. So, we flipped 91
for 117, I think, or whatever it was,
part of the Vegas trade. Um we're
picking 106, 117. So, the players that
we're talking about tomorrow,
it's the same players that we would have
been talking about at 91. So, when you
look up there at the names, like we
would have picked one of the guys at 91
that's on the board that we're probably
going to talk about tomorrow. So,
that trade, similar to to the Butler's
trade, it was more about just
repositioning the picks cuz we really
didn't give anything up other than
slots. So, that's kind of how we view
it. Um so, you got a few picks tomorrow
to kind of play around with. Um we'll
see how it goes there um in the morning.
We you know, we're what, five or six
picks out. And then we have 117, then we
have the one in the fifth, the one in
the sixth, and then we have the seventh
round pick. So, we'll see how it all
kind of manifests itself tomorrow, comes
together. So, take some questions.
Do you um with Caden um
McDonald, were y'all surprised that he
was kind of dropping down and did that
factor in at all to why you all wanted
to trade up?
No, we I mean, look, I think sometimes
everybody gets this like, you know,
traded up. I mean, you move two spots. I
mean, you're not really doing anything.
You're just trying to make sure you get
the football player. So, we like the
player. Look, if a player falls, like we
can't control any of that. So, good
player, we do the evaluation. However we
get him in the building, we get him in
the building, we'll pick him.
Um again, visit with him, brought him in
the building. He was here at NRG, had a
good visit with him, kind of continuing
the process.
Did a lot of work on him, have a lot of
respect for Coach Day and his program.
We have a lot of people at Ohio State
that we know at say in a pretty deep
level. Um whether it's coaching staff,
you know, Coach Patricia, Coach Day,
have some folks on the strength staff,
they have some people on the training
staff. You know, Nate Ebner was involved
in the program a little bit this year
who
you know, I was with Nate um in New
England there for a little bit. So,
when you have people like that, when
they tell you something, okay, what
they're telling you, you can probably
trust. So, to have that type of
relationship and be able to have that
information kind of solidified what we
thought and where we think the player
is. Um so,
um yeah, I mean, he was a player that we
liked. Again, like we felt he was like
the best run-stopping defensive tackle
in the draft. So, all right, well, then
let's if we have an opportunity to add
that player, then let's go ahead and add
him to the team, which is what we did. I
was saying like were you surprised cuz
obviously you loved him that he was like
falling a little bit?
>> Again, we can't control any of that.
Like it's not up to us. So, if a
player's available, so we'll look at
what our options are.
Um we had a few players um at 38 and 36,
whatever it was. Probably like two or
three guys, like, all right, we have a
chance to pick one of these guys. All
right, let's go ahead and pick him.
And then, you know, that's why we made
the pick that we did. With respect to
McDonald, do you think there's more
ahead of him in terms of pass rush? We
saw a lot of run stopping from him, and
sometimes he gets to the quarterback. Do
you think there's more ahead of him as
he refines and continues to be around
your coaches?
>> Yeah, we'll see. I think the big thing
you got to play to your strengths. So,
what a player does well, let's let's
accentuate the strengths. And then, if
the guy has an area that he can improve,
then see if we can get him to improve. I
think sometimes it's
even a player has a perception, well, I
want to be able to do this. Well, okay,
look, you're 6'3" 330 lbs. The best
thing you do is play strong at the point
of attack. So, your pass rush is
probably going to be a little bit
different than, you know, Denico Autry
or somebody else that's rushing inside
there. So, you have to play to your
strengths. And then, our coaches, I
mean, look, we got the best defensive
coaching staff in the league. So, they
probably got the best defensive line
coach in the league in Rod and Coach
Okum. So, we're going to figure out a
way to get the player to play within our
system and in our scheme and try to
figure out like how we can utilize his
strengths and try to improve the areas
that we feel need to improve.
So, when you think about the overall
defensive line where you're at right now
with the edges that you have and having
the D-tackle rotation, how are you
feeling about the defensive line overall
that you have right now?
Yeah, we'll see. I mean, we feel we'll
have a competitive defensive line, and
each week is going to change relative to
who the opponent is. So, the bottom line
in this league, like you got to be able
to stop the run, you got to be able to
take the ball away, and you got to keep
points off the scoreboard. So,
that's what defensive football is about.
So, however you do that,
like that's your ultimate your
responsibility. From a
football standpoint, um
you guys since DeMeco's been DeMeco's
been here, but at the D-tackle spot,
most of them kind of range around 300
lbs, a little bit higher, a little bit
lower. Obviously, McDonald's closer to
330.
Um how much do you think that body type
can put that unlock a different type of
approach that you guys may want to do
um in terms of using a bigger body um
up, you know, in a one-tech, zero-tech,
things that need to be done?
>> Yeah, I think well, DeMeco and I have
talked continuously. There's a place for
that player in this front. I think
there's a perception of, well, he just,
you know, want a bunch of guys that just
like sprint off the ball and, you know,
don't have enough playing strength and
all that. Well,
in the end, you got to be able to play
strong at the point of attack. So,
you're going to have to I mean, Foley's
a good example. Like Foley, you know,
whatever size he was or I mean, Caden
McDonald are about not the same size,
but pretty close. So, there is a place
for that player on the inside part of
the defense, especially on early downs.
And then, how do you utilize that player
in in, let's say, known passing
situations or on third down? Maybe
there's another option, or maybe there's
a situation that you can create a
matchup with that player. So, we've
talked extensively that there is a place
for that type of player, that body body
type in in this system, and we don't
want to cast a player aside because he
maybe quote-unquote doesn't fit the
profile. So, um and I think that's the
beauty of our like defense and like
DeMeco is constantly looking for ways to
evolve, and we're just not so beholden
to well, this is the way it was three or
four years ago. I mean, our defense has
evolved, our team has evolved, and we
need to continue to evolve
as a team and as an organization. And
so, with to your question, I think
sometimes it's like, well, does a player
like this fit in this front? You know, I
mean, the answer is absolutely yes.
Okay, Marlon Mack's case because
his his
tran- maturation, he hadn't played a
whole lot of football compared to speak
to a kid coming from the US.
Is that Does that Did that propose any
issues with y'all as far as the amount
of football he's been played up until
this point? Or are you just looking at
the upside of him? Yeah, not
necessarily. I mean, you have players
with varied backgrounds. You have some
players that have been really successful
in this league who didn't even play
college football. And you know, some
people they only played high school
football. Marlon at least played, even
though he grew up maybe not
foot- not going to say football is
foreign to him, but he wasn't thinking
about playing probably in the NFL when
he was growing up in Germany. And then
he came to the States, and then his
career kind of evolved and grew.
And he spent three or four years,
however many years it was, at Michigan,
which has a good program, and they had a
pretty good track record of tight ends
over the course of however many last
years. I mean, between Schoonmaker,
Colson last year, I mean, they've had a
of I'd say good players at that
position. He played behind some pretty
good players. Had his opportunity here
this year, took advantage of his
opportunity. Um, I'd say they were
definitely more of a running offense.
So, you know, can he improve and grow? I
think he definitely has the mentality
and the mindset to take coaching. He
understands football. He understands
concepts. So, what you're looking is the
player have the willingness and the
drive to actually work to improve. And
I'd say in Marlyn's case, it certainly
appears that way. Now, what that
actually looks like, we'll find out here
as we go.
Mention having a couple of deals in
place. Were you all trying to move down
at that at 59 at that point? We were
looking at both. I mean, I think this
draft is kind of emblematic of who we
are. What we looked up, we had
opportunities to go up. I mean, I think
we walked in the draft room, I think we
put like 10 boxes on the board. Like we
had a hey, here's the trade down group.
Here's the trade up group. All right,
what's real, what's not. I mean, we
probably talked, I don't want to say
half the league, we probably talked to
half the league here, you know, over the
course of the day. What's your appetite
for moving up? All right, got it. All
right, if we want to move up, what would
that look like? All right, if we, let's
say we don't pick at 38 and we end up
moving back, what does that look like?
So, and that's kind of how we how we
approach it. And you can have it then.
I'm just curious if your process is
like,
you know, when you when you guys have a
guy high on your board, but maybe you
might I don't know how you guys view
other
I don't know how you find out what other
teams are thinking or what other NFL
>> call them and ask them what they're
doing, but
>> yeah, so like but like how do you how do
you
you see like a lot of people think this
person might be lower, but we have this
guy higher. How do you determine whether
okay, we want to take a chance here even
though other people could believe he
might be lower. How do you make that
>> Yeah, I think the beauty of all this
everybody kind of has their own board.
So, you have your grades. You're
probably not grading all the players the
same way. I think when you go through
this third round, I mean, the reality is
I mean, they were basically coming out
of the woodwork in this past but this
last round. So, there's a lot of players
that got drafted where you're looking up
there going, oh okay, we probably
wouldn't have taken that that player.
And maybe there's a few players oh, we'd
consider him. So,
we just kind of go through our process,
grade the players, and create kind of
categories and buckets of players. All
right, if this pick, all right, here's
three or four names. All right, we're
comfortable picking one of them. All
right, if you move back and still get
one of them, are we good with that or
would we rather move and I'd say in
Caden's case, hey, let's move up a
little bit because there's a player that
we sort of identified. Look, what other
teams are going to do like honestly like
for somebody to sit here and tell you
like yeah, they knew what they were
going to do, I mean, they're lying. I
I'm not going to tell you that. I mean,
you're trying to project to some degree.
That's why we go through the pro staff
does an incredible job of like looking
at team. Hey, here's what we think their
needs are. What we think their needs are
might be different from what that team's
needs or what they think they are. So,
look, this is a big puzzle. You're
trying to piece it together. There's
probably a thousand pieces
and there's never one particular piece
that ultimately is going to be the
deciding factor, the driving force. You
guys have moved up twice already in this
draft and it's because of the
aggressiveness that you you've targeted
players that you really like. When it
comes to day three, do you feel like
that because of you mentioned that picks
at 91, they may be the same players that
you're targeting around 96. Is it easier
or a little bit more challenging to get
aggressive for guys on day three?
It doesn't change. And again, I'm not
trying to minimize like moving, but like
moving two spots in our mind is
basically nothing. Like we don't view it
that way. I think when you start moving
eight to 10 spots, that's a little bit
more of a probably a calculated move
where you're probably going to have to
give up
a little bit more capital.
I would say again, this is just how we
view it. You know, moving two spots and
repositioning picks, you don't really
give anything up other than draft slots.
So,
again, yeah, we moved up a few spots. Is
that us being aggressive? No, I think
it's more of us just sort of being
strategic about like what we feel like
makes the most sense and what we need to
do. When you're making a big jump, I
would put the, you know, look, I would
put the Will move into that was an
aggressive move because we moved like a
significant amount of spots.
Moving two to three spots, it's just
more about positioning. That's kind of
how we talk about it as a staff. Um,
it'll be the same thing tomorrow. So,
we're 106, you know, like does it make
sense to move a couple spots? Then it's
like, all right, how do we reconstitute
those picks? So, I think it'll be the
same thought process tomorrow as it's
been the fact the past few days. You
think there's some little difference
every day
pretty transparent on this one. Did
anyone call you about Nico Collins and
then was that just something kind of
random or not not anything to that? And
why would you want to trade Nico Collins
if someone did want to call and talk
about that hypothetically? Yeah, I mean,
look, teams call teams all the time and
ask about players. I mean, we're not
trading Nico Collins. So, I mean, like
whoever reported it or whatever
information that they had, I mean, I
mean,
they could take it and shove it. Like
we're not trading Nico.
A lot of money. I I obviously, you know,
past few years teams have
defense have kind of countered the
explosive passing attack by playing more
two high safety shells and obviously
offenses have kind of countered that by
trying to run more downhill. So, did did
that kind of help in I want to say
elevate McDonald's value knowing that
how teams want to play now, how deep the
deep well, teams want to attack you guys
specifically, um, knowing to have a guy
like that and um
that can I guess, you know, in a sense
be so good at stopping the run when
teams are trying to play more two high
safety looks and have those guys in the
middle to be able to counter that.
Yeah, I think our mentality on defense
is to play fast, violent, and physical.
So, who are the players that have those
qualities? Then forget about scheme,
forget about other teams are doing,
start with that premise,
fill the players in, and then whoever we
play each week,
it's going to be the same thing. Like
we're going to have to be good in the
running game, we're going to minimize
big plays, and we're going to have to
play well in the red area. And defense
is about points and red area is about
points. So, it's it's more of the hey,
here's what we want our defense to be
about. Here are the things that we
emphasize. All right, who are those
players that actually fit? Like we pride
ourselves in being
Um, and that's not going to change. I
mean, as long as DeMeco's the head
coach, as long as we're here running the
team, we're going to prioritize
toughness and physicality. So, let's
find the players that have those
attributes. And if you you want to be a
big, strong, tough, physical team, you
better have big, strong, tough, physical
players that enable you to play a
certain way cuz in the end, that's what
wins in this league.
All right. Thank you. Yep. Thanks.